<resources>
    <string name="app_name">FinanceSmart</string>
    <string name="startAppButtonText">Continue</string>
    <string name="take_home">Enter your monthly take home</string>
    <string name="Title">Taking the reigns on your personal finance</string>
    <string name="Description">The key to sound financial footing in life begins with knowing where your money is coming from and where it is going and the best way to begin this
    is with budgeting. This not only involves attempting to minimise outgoings the best you can but also with figuring out your goals and what the best strategy is going forward
    to reach those. This app is designed to help you help you realise your spending and gain knowledge on how moving forward your money may better be put to work for you.</string>
    <string name="takehomeTitle">Starting from the beginning</string>
    <string name="takehomeDescription">Controlling your finances begins at the source. Enter below the average total monthly net income you receive. Thats your income you see
    coming in after those taxes but before any bills are removed such as food, rent/mortgages and council tax. We need to start with this to compare spending to income and to
    calculate how much we can contribute to debts and goals.</string>
    <string name="takehomeEnter">Enter</string>
    <string name="takehomeHint">Monthly take home</string>
    <string name="emergencyfundTitle">Forecasting a rainy day</string>
    <string name="emergencyfundDescription">No one likes to think about it but sometimes things dont go in our favour. In the UK around 26% people have savings of less than £1,000. Take a moment to think about how long this would last you if say from tomorrow your income disappeared. Stashing away an \'emergency fund\' is vital to protecting yourself and family from loss of income or unexpected bills such as a car breakdown. Depending on your risk appetite this amount should be between a months outgoings up to 6 months. This not only helps avoid panicking in desperate times this will allow you to avoid dangerous pay day loans or borrowing and instead gives you peace of mind. Enter below the amount you currently have saved and lets see how much you might more you might need to put away or if you on track</string>
    <string name="emergencyfundHint">Emergency fund saved</string>
    <string name="emergencyfundEnter">Enter</string>
    <string name="outgoingsTitle">Where did that paycheck go?</string>
    <string name="outgoingsDescription">Have you ever looked at your account and wondered why your balance never seems to be going up? This is down to one simple fact but
        one that we often turn a blind eye to or do not realise. Your outgoing payments are greater than the incoming ones! This can be down to many factors but is a recipe
        for future disaster if not remedied. In the box below input your average monthly spend or all the payments coming out of your accounts such as debts, internet, car payments
        clothes, coffees etc.</string>
    <string name="outgoingsHint">Monthly outgoings</string>
    <string name="highInterestDebtTitle">Money pits</string>
    <string name="highInterestDebtDescription">Before anyone can think about long term saving and investing its best to remove any short term leaks and get debts payed off. enter yes or no below if you have any high interest debt (>4%) excluding student loans</string>
    <string name="highInterestDebtButton">Continue</string>
    <string name="highInterestDebtSwitchNo">No</string>
    <string name="highInterestDebSwitchYes">Yes</string>
    <string name="HighInterestDebt">High Interest Debt</string>
    <string name="pensionSchemeTitle">Thinking of the future</string>
    <string name="pensionSchemeDescription">For many people retirement feels like another lifetime away but it is never too early to consider your future self. The best thing you can do for this is to ensure you are enrolled in a pension scheme for your workplace and recieving the best contributions you can from your employer. This will set you up great for later life and if you already doing this then thats great! Enter below if you know whether or not your giving the max contributions to your workplace pension</string>
    <string name="pensionSchemeToggle">Pension scheme contribution</string>
    <string name="pensionSchemeToggleYes">Yes</string>
    <string name="pensionSchemeToggleNo">No</string>
    <string name="pensionSchemeButton">Continue</string>
    <string name="firstHomeTitle">Flying the nest</string>
    <string name="firstHomeDescription">Purchasing a house is often the top priority for many people and likely to be the biggest purchase they will make in their lives. Saving for a deposit and any relevant fees can depend on time frames and cost so it can be reassuring to know you are saving in the most effective way possible for the future. Enter below if you are saving currently for your first home along with the time frame in which you intend to purchase.</string>
    <string name="firstHomeSwitchYes">Yes</string>
    <string name="firstHomeSwitchNo">No</string>
    <string name="firstHomeSwitch">Saving for your first Home?</string>
    <string name="firstHomeInput">Years until purchase</string>
    <string name="firstHomeButton">Continue</string>
    <string name="highInterestDebtName">Debt name</string>
    <string name="highInterestDebtMin">Min payment</string>
    <string name="highInterestDebtRate">%</string>
    <string name="highInterestDebtAmount">Amount to pay</string>
    <string name="addDebtButton">Add</string>
    <string name="delDebtButton">X</string>
    <string name="shortTermTitle">Setting up goals</string>
    <string name="shortTermDescription">Having something to work towards is key for motivating to save and show yourself that you can be financially responsible. Enter below if you have any short term goals ( less than 5 years and excluding buying a home).</string>
    <string name="shortTermToggle">Short term goals?</string>
    <string name="shortTermContinue">Continue</string>
    <string name="shortTermToggleYes">Yes</string>
    <string name="shortTermToggleNo">No</string>
    <string name="longTermTitle">Thinking further ahead</string>
    <string name="longTermDescription">As we mentioned earlier about setting up your workplace pensions and ensuring maximum contributions, Thinking of the future is absolutely vital to not only look after your future self but give your current self piece of mind and reassurance. Enter below if you have any longer terms goals and whether these occur before or after you reach retirement account so we can find the best options.</string>
    <string name="longTermSwitch">Long term goals? (More than 5 years)</string>
    <string name="longTermSwitchAge">After retirement age? (~58)</string>
    <string name="longTermContinue">Continue</string>
    <string name="title_activity_summary">ScrollingActivity</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="takeHomeSummaryTitle">Your monthly take home</string>
    <string name="outgoingsSummaryTitle">Your monthly outgoings</string>
    <string name="emergencyFundSummaryTitle">That rainy day fund</string>
    <string name="outgoingsSummaryDescriptionNegative">Your monthly expenses are %d%% of what you take home. This is higher than ideal so we should look at where your spending is going and try to bring it below 50%% if we can!</string>
    <string name="outgoingsSummaryDescriptionPositive">Your monthly expenses are %d%% of what you take home. We\'re on track so far and your spending is not out of control!</string>
    <string name="emergencyFundReached">Well done! you\'ve achieved your target of £%1$d (6 months outgoings). Now keep this set aside in an account you can easily access quickly and has a good interest rate to earn a return on this. </string>
    <string name="emergencyFundLacking">Your target of £%1$d has not quite been reached yet. Try and set some more aside each month if you can to build this up closer to the target of 6 months outgoings.</string>
    <string name="takeHomeSummary">£%1$d</string>
    <string name="outgoingsSummary">£%1$d</string>
    <string name="pensionSummaryTitle">Pension Contributions</string>
    <string name="pensionSummaryGood">You stated that you apply the maximum contribution to your workplace pension including matched contributions. This is great news and is sure you set you up well for the future should you continue.</string>
    <string name="pensionSummaryBad">You\'ve stated you dont yet give your maximum contribution or are unsure. Make it your mission to find out what your employer offers and look into getting the benefits of this scheme!</string>
    <string name="debtSummaryTitle">Draining debts</string>
    <string name="debtSummaryButton">Get advice</string>
    <string name="firstHomeSummaryTitle">Joining the property ladder</string>
    <string name="debtsPresentSummary">It looks like you have some higher interest debts that could do with wiping out to restore some of your monthly income. Click the get advice button below to find out how to tackle these debts best.</string>
    <string name="debtsAbsentSummary">You didn\'t enter any high interest debts previously. Thats great and we should aim to keep it this way if we can due to their potential drain on incomes</string>
    <string name="noFirstHome">You don\'t need to worry about this section!</string>
    <string name="longTermFirstHome">You\'ve entered that it will be around %d years until you purchase your first home. This is fairly long term and that money otherwise set in a savings or current account could be gaining more value. Consider a LISA for a 25%% bonus on up to £4000 a year and the rest could go placed into an index fund.</string>
    <string name="shortTermFirstHome">%d years isn\'t long term enough to be considering higher risk methods of gaining value. Aim to keep your deposit in a savings account with a respectable interest rate until you need the cash. You can still benefit from a LISA too if you aren\'t already!</string>
</resources>